HAKAN TUNCER

Date of Birth: August 9th, 1982 **Place of Birth:** Istanbul

Gender: Male

Permanent Address:

Amsterdam, NETHERLANDS **Mobile:** +31 64 3130353

E-mail: hakantuncer@gmail.com

Website/Blog:

http://hakantuncer.com/
Twitter: @hakant



I'm a passionate developer building quality software using my skills in .NET, node.js and web technologies (HTML, CSS, Javascript). I love C# and Javascript. I also like taking advantage of cloud platforms like Azure and AWS whenever suitable.

I write about my experiences in software development in my blog: http://hakantuncer.com/blog and I'm available for new projects: http://hakantuncer.com/blog

Education

2000-2005 Sabanci University

Istanbul, TURKEY

Faculty of Engineering & Natural Sciences Computer Science & Engineering Program GPA: 3.35/4.00 (Honours Degree)

Skills

The following table contains a list of technologies, platforms and patterns that I've got hands-on experience with:

	Technology, Platform, Pattern (per category)
Languages	C#, Javascript
Environments	Windows, Mac OS, Powershell, Bash
Main Platforms	.NET, Node.js, Xamarin Android
Backend Frameworks	ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web API, ExpressJS, NancyFX
IoC, ORM	Ninject, Autofac, Simple Injector, LLBLGen, Entity Framework
Frontend Frameworks	AngularJS, Knockout.js, Aurelia
Testing	WebDriver, Protractor, NUnit, XUnit, Jasmine
SQL	Microsoft SQL Server, Azure SQL Database

NoSQL	Azure DocumentDb, AWS DynamoDb, MongoDb, Redis
Other Storage	Azure Blob Storage, AWS S3, Azure Table Storage
Cloud - Azure	Cloud Services, App Services, Service Fabric
Cloud - AWS	EC2, Elastic Beanstalk
Architecture	Component Based, N-Tier, Domain Driven Design, (Micro)Service Oriented, Message Bus, Event Driven and Reactive

Work Experience

2011 – Present NIPO Software Grote Bickersstraat 74, 1013KS Amsterdam, NL Team Architect - Senior Software Developer

- At NIPO Software, I'm building a "software as a service" data collection platform for market research industry. This platform is called Nfield; a high-traffic, high-scale service that runs on Microsoft Azure and processes large volumes of data. Nfield is currently serving hundreds of large market research companies in three different regions (US, APAC and Europe).
- I'm using Visual Studio 2015 and Visual Studio Code.
- I'm using Visual Studio Team Services (TFS in the cloud) for Version Control, Product Backlog, Canvas Board and Application Lifecycle Management activities.
- I'm using GitHub with GitFlow as development workflow.
- I'm using AppVeyor build system for Continuous Integration & Delivery.
- I do a lot of back-end development. Scalability, resilience and fault tolerance are very important in the cloud. I use Service Bus, Message Queues, Cache Service, NoSQL and Blob Storage together with Azure SQL Databases.
- I'm building around PaaS capabilities of Windows Azure. The application consists of various cloud service nodes with different types (web and worker roles). I'm closely watching every new feature in Azure since it's the cloud platform of our choice.
- I'm building on top of ASP.NET MVC 4 and 5. Using C# and Razor View Engine. Heavily using Web API's and the OWIN pipeline.
- I'm writing a lot of Javascript. Client facing websites that I'm building are completely driven by Javascript and all data is received and sent via AJAX calls to the back-end.

- I'm applying the MVVM pattern on client side with Knockout.js. Talking to Web APIs in JSON. Parts of the UI are written using other Javascript templating libraries. Specifically JSRender and Handlebars.
- I'm working in a SCRUM environment. Product Backlog, User Stories, Grooming Sessions, Spikes, Epics, 2 week sprints are often used terms in my daily life.
- I'm doing Unit Testing using the Moq Framework and XUnit family runners (sometimes MSTest too). I'm trying to cover as much code as possible without losing common sense. I like tools like NCrunch that continuously runs tests in the background as I write code.
- Apart from Unit Tests I also write Integration Tests and UI Tests. I use Selenium WebDriver and Protractor for my UI tests.
- I'm practicing TDD both for Unit and Integration Testing whenever it fits nicely with the code / feature that I'm working on.
- I'm also actively working on a mobile application for Android devices. Using Xamarin, C# and Nancy. This is a native application with embedded HTML user interface (like Ionic or Cordova).
- I've also written social applications that integrates with Facebook and Twitter APIs.

2008 – 2011 about:blank

Schellingweg 17D, 1507DR Zaandam, NL

Senior Software Developer

- Architecting, developing, testing and delivering web applications (mainly ASP.NET and Microsoft SQL Server based) for various customers from various industries.
- Applications include online reservation systems, web shops, social networking sites, job boards and online bidding systems with different functional, performance and scalability challenges.

2007 – 2008 Oxivo Software

Atasehir, Istanbul, TURKEY

Software Developer

- Architecting, developing, testing and delivering web applications (mainly ASP.NET and Microsoft SQL Server based) for various customers from various industries.
- In charge of technical communication between Turkey and Netherlands.
- I've built various applications including "Findsi", a socially enhanced search and bookmarking tool, "Friendhunter", a social job board & employment website, "Veiling Winnaar", an online bidding system, "All abc houses", a large housing website.

2006 – 2007 Oleey Mobile

3.Levent, Istanbul, TURKEY

Software Engineer

- I joined an early start-up of a leading media group in Turkey, that entered the mobile content market by selling games, melodies and wallpapers to millions of mobile subscribers of GSM operators in Turkey.
- I built three separate SMS & charging integrations from scratch with three different GSM operators in Turkey (Turkcell, Vodafone and Avea).
- I also wrote a content management system for mobile devices along with a WAP and a WEB portal for promoting content to the end users.
- All software systems were built on ASP.NET, Windows Services (using C# language) & MS SQL Server and deployed on multiple Windows 2003 servers.

2005-2006 Tikle – Arti Technology

Ari Teknokent, Istanbul, TURKEY

Software Developer

- Joined a team of ~20 developers and worked on several WEB, WAP and SMS portals used for promoting and selling mobile content to mobile subscribers. Also took part in a J2ME (Java Micro Edition) game development project for a period of time.
- All projects (except mobile game which was in Java), were based on .NET Framework and MS SQL Server.
- Some of my main projects were "Resimmelodi" and "Oyunparki". Former is a wallpaper and melody portal and latter was a game portal.
- For the first time I found the opportunity to work in a professional team of developers, build applications and portals, develop my programming skills and gain experience on the subject of mobile portal design and development.